ERIX GUTIERREZ

Full-Stack Developer

- **+58-0424-4607888**
- ∂ https://github.com/erixAlexander
- Caracas, Venezuela

- @ erix.gutierrez@gmail.com
- Phttps://linkedin.com/in/erix-gutierrez-652a75201
- ☆ Portfolio: https://zingy-mochi-619c8f.netlify.app



SUMMARY

Resourceful Developer with 9+ years of experience in Frontend development, with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, and Backend Development with Nodejs. Skilled at utilizing a wide variety of tools and programs to create effective applications. Also a background in presales engineering leading a team of specialists working with sales teams, and conducting presentations to promote a new app or program to customers.

EXPERIENCE

Solutions Senior Leader

GB Advisors LLC

🛱 2019 - Present

Miami, FL

GB Advisors is a Leading Software Solutions company devoted to the advisory and implementation of ITSM and Digital Security solutions.

- Support the sales team all throughout the sales process and function as the technical resource for the team and the technical point of contact for the prospects improving sales by 60%
- Hired, coached and led solutions team to close deals and improve customer satisfaction, software sales improved by more than 50% every year
- Developed and maintained 10+ API integrations using Python, JavaScript for national and foreign clients
- · Created python scripts to automate processes and integrate apps in Zapier
- Established and lead a team of 10 people; covering every key role in the early stages

Front End Web Developer

Grupo Innova CA

苗 2013 - 2019 👂 Caracas, DF

Grupo Innova is a software developing company dedicated to creating and maintaining web and mobile applications.

- Designed and collaborated in +5 mobile apps UI and 30+ web applications using React and React Native
- Reviewed code, debugged problems and corrected issues in my code and other team members code
- Developed web scraping program in Python to link it to an API for a client's website's comsumption
- Ensured that the user interfaces and user experience of the software integrations developed by the team met at least 90% of users expectations
- Influenced more than 4 different teams at different points of time and provided end-to-end solutions for clients

WordPress Developer

TST Solutions RL

苗 2010 - 2013 👂 Valencia, CA

TST Solutions is a technology company that specializes in IT, networks, and software development.

- · Automated IT and Security processes in company processes
- · Implemented and delivered projects directly with the biggest customers
- Implemented and advised in projects that ended well ahead of time which saved costs by at least 20%
- Reduced databases size by nearly 50% and improved its performance by 20%
- Delivery time of products reduced by at least 30%
- Collaborate with developers and product management team to assess project outcomes and prioritize future app features
- · Reduced page load time of homepage by 20% by optimizing mySQL queries

SKILLS

Python	JavaScript		React
React-Native		Web Services/API	
HTML5	CSS	SQL	MongoDB
Redux			

EDUCATION

College Degree - Telecommunications Engineer

UNEFA

Front-End developer Specialization - by META

Coursera

 https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishmen ts/specialization/certificate/SLWHXTM8X4ZM

ServiceNow CSA Certificate

Service Now

STRENGTHS

Problem-solving

Identifying the root and cause of a problem not only in the code but any problem that can arise



Delegate, inspire, motivate and communicate effectively

Always Improving

Always studying and learning new things, that is my passion, love to find out about new technologies

ACHIEVEMENTS

₽

Recognized

Excellence Award year 2020, by GB Advisors

Customer Satisfaction

At least 99% of customers are satisfied and happy with the results and products delivered

Powered by CY Enhancy